Employee onboarding should create confidence.
But for growing teams, the first days are often
scattered across messages and spreadsheets.
And disconnected documents. That is why
we built Simple Board:
a native macOS onboarding workspace
for small team owners and their employees.
Here is the Sunrise Bistro demo.
From one dashboard, an owner can see
active employees, published programs, completion,
and people who may need support.
The manager opens Kitchen Staff Onboarding.
Programs are organized into stages
with deadlines, clear outcomes,
and seven learning formats:
video, reading, checklist, quiz,
task, document, and meeting.
Preview mode lets the manager experience the journey
safely without changing any employee record.
On the employee record, the owner can see
the assigned program, stage progress,
and completion evidence. Now we switch
to the employee point of view.
Budi signs in with his own account
and immediately sees one focused journey,
his progress, and the next action to complete.
Budi acknowledges the Kitchen Code of Conduct.
His progress moves from seventy-one
to eighty-six percent. When the owner returns,
the dashboard already shows the updated result.
The Performance view turns that activity
into a clear signal:
who is on track, who has completed onboarding,
and who needs help.
We built Simple Board in Codex.
We started from a browser prototype
and asked Codex to help turn it
into a real native SwiftUI application.
Codex worked directly inside the repository:
creating the Xcode project, typed data models,
an observable application store, local persistence,
Keychain credentials, responsive macOS layouts,
previews, the employee portal,
and automated tests.
Our workflow was iterative. Codex inspected screenshots,
reproduced layout defects, and changed the SwiftUI code.
It ran Xcode builds and tests, then used the evidence
to refine the next pass.
That let one small team move from idea to a working,
TestFlight-ready Mac app much faster.
GPT-5.6 was the reasoning layer
throughout that process.
It translated product goals into a safe owner
and employee permission model,
designed local-first storage and secure invitations,
and traced difficult layout and state bugs.
It also planned end-to-end test coverage.
We used it as an engineering partner:
describe the intent, reason over the code,
verify the result, and iterate.
Simple Board makes onboarding clear for leaders
and actionable for employees.
Because every first day should feel
like the company was ready for you.